# Keshav Raj

keshav.rajsspn@gmail.com | +91-9576640200 | linkedin.com/in/k-e-s-h-a-v | github.com/k-e-s-h-a-v

#### **SUMMARY**

Ambitious Data Engineer with 3+ years of experience in building high-performance data platforms, specializing in decentralized architectures (DataMesh) with Data Governance and optimizing business intelligence systems. Successfully led teams, was quick to adapt to challenging environments and contributed to product acquisition

## **EDUCATION**

#### Bhagalpur College of Engineering, Bhagalpur

Jul 2018 - Sept 2022

B. Tech in Electrical Engineering

CGPA: 8.2

### Sainik School Punglwa Nagaland, Ministry of Defence

May 2010 - June 2017

Science, High School Education

Percentage: 81.2

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Infor Jul 2024 - Present

Hyderabad, India

Software Engineer
Integrated Apache Superset using Delta Lake to the DataMesh platform for real-time data visualization.

• Built an invoice processing system with Qwen to extract data that feeds an event-driven, configurable data entry pipeline, reducing SLA from 48 hours to 1.5 minutes.

albanero (acquired by Infor) Jun 2021 - Jul 2024

Hyderabad, India

• Software Engineer II (6 months)

Jan 2024 - Jul 2024

- Key contributor to a **state-of-the-art DataMesh platform**, later acquired by Infor.
- Slashed memory usage by 90% in the CSV-to-Excel pipeline. eg: 52 GB to 4 GB for  $\approx 3$  million records.
- Enabled multi-CSV merging into a single Excel file, with each CSV as a dedicated sheet.

• Team Lead (8 months)

May 2023 - Jan 2024

- Led a team of **data analysts** to deliver **high-impact products**, including two key projects—one was live in just **6 weeks**.
- Built a data mastering system using the Jaro-Winkler algorithm for duplicate detection.
- Standardized entity names using **NER** with **spaCy**, and integrated **Loqute** for **address verification**.
- Conducted internal training sessions on our **DataMesh platform**, teaching teams how to use its **decentralized** architecture and scalable workflows.
- Software Engineer I (8 months)

Sep 2022 - May 2023

- Built a dynamic **SQL** query generator to search/filter millions of records.
- Software Engineer Intern (1 year 4 months)

Jun 2021 - Sep 2022

- o Developed Identity Access Management (IAM) for DataMesh, including role-permission logic.
- Authored feature for real-time status updates for data transformation workflows using Socket.io.
- Implemented multi-theme support in a SaaS platform, standardized SCSS practices, and gained hands-on experience with JavaScript.

## **PROJECTS**

#### VS Code Extensions

- Explorer Plus **6**: Supercharges the VS Code file explorer with file/folder stats and sort.
- Code Folder Summary **3**: Shows a quick overview of file types in a project.
- File Size and Count **@**: Displays file/folder size and count on hover.

**Chrome Extension** 

• Read Canvas • A Chrome Extension for reading the captcha from canvas. See it in action

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Python, SQL, JavaScript

Libraries/Frameworks: PySpark, FastAPI, Flask, Docker

BI/Analytics Tools: Apache Superset, AWS Athena, Delta Lake (Parquet), MongoDB

Tech: Git, Data Modeling, ETL Pipelines, Data Security, Data Federation

# **CERTIFICATES**

An Introduction to Artificial Intelligence  $\mathscr{O}$ Programming, Data Structures and Algorithms using Python  $\mathscr{O}$ Data Analytics at E & ICT Academy  $\mathscr{O}$ 

IIT Delhi IIT Madras IIT Kanpur